Alok Ranjan

13 Years Of
Experience As A Full
Stack Developer &
Data Scientist

Contact

Address

Noida, UP, 201306

Phone

704 291 5552

E-mail

alokranjan04@gmail.com

WWW

alokranjan04.github.com

Skills

Python

Very Good

Machine learning

Good

Elastic search

Good

React hooks

Good

AngularJS

Very Good

Javascript

Very Good

Go-lang

Enthusiastic Project Engineer with 13 years of experience. Adept at Project design ,Full Stack web development, AI and machine learning implementation for automating the process and quality control support with excellent multitasking skills. Successful at contracting and field support with knowledge of Javascript, Python, Go , Angular ,React & Elasticsearch

Experienced Software Engineer with over 13 years of experience in Software Industry. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements. Consistently saved costs while increasing profits.

Work History

2015-10 -Current

Data Scientist

Concentrix, Noida, UP

- Established chatbot frameworks for Covid-19 support using RASA.
- Developed another **Chatbot** using **Elasticsearch**.
- Developed basic kids App & questionnaire App in Flutter.
- Developed chat application using qr-code scanner in Go-lang for login & sendTextMessage API.
- Designed and developed PDF smart search
 application using pytessaract, glove embeddings,
 word2vec embedings, pickle saving the model and
 cosine similarity which gives Page No, Para No.
 ,Line No for the nearest match for word/phrase
 /sentence search.
- Designed and developed PDF smart search application using python, pandas & Elasticsearch.
- Built word corrector using nltk which predicts the nearby words with its percentage similarity.
- As full stack developer, built chat notification application in Angular 8 and web workers.
- Built my own site https://www.tyjnews.com using
 React hooks and highcharts.
- Built tracking chrome extension and its dashboard using Jquery, Javascript, Google sheet, Google App script and data transformation using google colab.
- Built general purpose chrome extension for capturing all kinds of details from the page as well

Average Chrome Extension development Verv Good Al & Deep Learning Good NLP Good **IBM Watson** Average Flutter Good Software Developmen Very Good Project Planning and Development Skills Very Good Teamwork / Collaboration

as **event handling** like button **click** and mouseover and saving the same in initially using **localstorage** but afterwards using **indexeddb** in the browser.

- Created positive environment in my organisation using Lets-do attitude.
- Coached, developed and motivated team
 members, providing coaching and mentoring to UI
 Developers and junior data scientists on web
 development, service worker notification and
 chatbots techniques.

2014-03 - UI Developer

2015-08

2012-02

CA Technology, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Designed UIs within frontend web frameworks such as AngularJS, exploiting associated templates and tools to shorten development times.
- Developed Application UIs via emerging Front End Technologies such as AngularJS
- Communicated with product managers and UX
 designers to translate project requirements and
 business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Improved and expanded project platforms using JavaScript to develop rich User Interfaces.
- Executed requirement analysis for Enterprise Mobile Application projects based in programming languages such as AngularJS, NodeJS, coffeescript and HAML.

2013-02 - **Software Consultant**

2014-03 MobileOps, Bangalore , CA

Developed Enterprise Mobile Application for usage analysis & crash analysis in **AngularJS**, **HTML**, **CSS** & **Javascript**

2011-03 - **Software Engineer**

ABB Global Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

- Developed Asset Management Apps, building framework for optimising physical resources used in different power sectors
- Used web technology like HTML, CSS, JS and JQuery to build the web apps

2010-04 - **UI Developer**

2011-12	WDC Technology, Bangalore Worked for telecom client ,building web app for the same , worked on browser compatibility, infinite scroll on web page using HTML, CSS, Jquery , Javascript
2007-07 - 2010-03	Software Engineer Tarams Software Technologies, Bangalore • Worked closely with software development and

 Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.

 Worked on Struts1.2, Javascript, HTML, CSS to develop a education based web application

Education

2003-08 - Bachelor of Engineering: Electrical Engineering

BMS Institute Of Technology - Bangalore

Accomplishments

 Collaborated with team of 200 agents, built their live tracking system in the development of Youtube
 Admin & videos verification

Certifications

2019-06 Deep learning Certification2017-06 Javascript Codility Award

Interests

Learning new language, Exercise, reading PMA books